# Himanshu Soni

# Full Stack Developer

## Resume Summary

Entrepreneurial mindset and a strong desire to learn from others in order to grow. I am able to work autonomously with a hacker's mindset, and have excellent problem-solving abilities. I have a can-do attitude and am not afraid to make mistakes. Additionally, I am a collaborative team player with great communication and time management skills. I also have experience working with growing startups.

## Work Experience

#### Roado

Software Developer Full-Time

01/2022 - present

- Developed geofencing feature with GPS for fleet tracking and notifications for deviations from defined routes or prolonged stops.
- Built Dealer module to facilitate communication between industries.
- Restructured application to support multiple sources and destinations and added multilevel filters for indents, assignments, and tracking.
- Revamped the UI and functionality of the assignment module, resulting in a significant 62% improvement in the overall user experience.
- Engineered Notification module including in-app notifications, emails, and SMS, as well as scheduled emails and SMS, SMS templates, custom reports, bulk upload, and long task reports.
- Created In Plant Management module for tracking processes within an industry, including gate in, loading, unloading, and gate out.
- Tech: MERN stack, GraphQL, TypeScript, Redis, AWS S3, Redux, PWA, Material UI.

#### Autowriter.ai / Product Description Generator

Full-Stack Developer Freelance

05/2021 - 01/2022

- Developed Shopify application that generated product descriptions and played a crucial role in its development.
- Maintained and improved GPT-3 APIs to achieve better results.
- Created new features for the application, such as shoppable social media feeds, category-specific descriptions, and multi-language support, leading to a 40% increase in user engagement.
- Ensured the application is user-friendly and easy to use.
- Collaborating with the team to troubleshoot and debug any issues that arose.
- Tech: Polaris, OAuth, Shopify App-Bridge, Express, GraphQL, RabbitMQ.

#### Data Analyst Intern, The Kabadiwala

Data Analyst Intern Full-Time

01/2021 - 05/2021

- Developed a constrained vehicle routing solution that has improved efficiency by 32% over manual routing.
- Established a data pipeline to validate the customer's address position.
- Developed compelling dashboards and reports to track key performance indicators, identify trends, and monitor business initiatives.
- $\bullet$  Tech: Predictive Analytics, Time Series Analysis, Pandas, NumPy, GitHub, Python, SQL.

### Education

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communications Medi-Caps University, Indore Specialization in Computer Technologies. 2016 – 2020 CGPA: 7.48/10

### **Projects**

#### Fuel Growth

- Provided seamless integration support for Shopify, Facebook, and actively involved in Google Analytics integration, harnessing data-driven strategies to optimize ecommerce performance.
- Tech: Python, Pandas, Django, Postgres, Celery, Shopify, Facebook, and Google Analytics.

#### 10xTechLabs

- Empowering software engineers with exponential career growth through a case study-based approach, fostering effectiveness and power in their professional journey.
- Developed MVP as a core team member at 10xTechLabs, handling frontend logics and backend.
- Tech: NX MonoRepo, React.js, Next.js, Caching, PostgreSQL, Rest API.

#### Skills

#### Frontend Technologies

- Markup & Styling: HTML, CSS, Markdown, SASS/SCSS
- Scripting: Javascript, Typescript
- Framework & Libraries: Nextjs, Reactjs, Three.js, Tailwind CSS, Material-UI
- Code Quality: ESlint, Prettier
- Web Technologies: Web Components, Service Workers
- Testing: Puppeteer, Jest

## Backend Technologies

- Core: Node.js, Python
- Frameworks: Express, DjangoOthers: Bash, JWT, OAuth
- Testing & Debugging: Jest, Visual Studio
- Message Broker: RabbitMQ

#### **Databases**

- SQL: MySQL, PostgresSQL
- NoSQL: MongoDBInMemory: Redis

#### Integrations

- Shopify
- Facebook/Meta
- Google Analytics
- OSRM/Nominatim

#### Other Technologies

- API Architecture: GraphQL, REST, WebSockets
- CI/CD: Jenkins
- Version Control System: Git
- Containers: Docker
- Orchestration: Kubernetes
- UI Design: Figma, Canva, Adobe XD

#### Cloud Platforms

- AWS: Lambda, S3, API Gateway
- Google Cloud Platform: OAuth2, Gmail API

#### Interests

Web Development and Design, Ecommerce, Augmented Reality, 3D Modeling, Immersive Technology like AR, VR, XR, and 3D websites.